Guide to the New York University Financial Ledgers RG.10.10
New York University Archives
New York University Financial Ledgers
1829-1960
New York University Archives
New York University
Bellevue Hospital Medical College
RG.10.10
48.2 Linear Feet in 39 boxes
The collection contains ledgers recording incnome, expenditures, vouchers, receipts and salary information pertaining to New York University between 1829 and 1960.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chonologically.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains ledgers recording incnome, expenditures, vouchers, receipts and salary information pertaining to New York University between 1829 and 1960.
Ledgers (account books); Education, Higher -- Finance; Universities and Colleges -- Finance
- Financial History, Rent Rolls and Collector's Accounts, Tenents' Agreements and Receipts, Trustees' Minutes on Financial History, 1830-1908 (Box 1)
- Subscription Book, 1829-1860s, 1881 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of Bills and Receipts (1 of 2), 1832-1841 (Box 8)
- Scrapbook of Bills and Receipts (2 of 2), 1832-1841 (Box 34)
- Grammar School Ledger, 1837-1844 (Box 5)
- Ledger of Rents, Fees, and Scholarships, 1838-1853 (Box 4)
- Receipt Book, 1839-1853 (Box 6)
- Tuition Payments, Fees, Scholarships by Class, 1853-1895 (Box 7)
- Subscription Books, Day Books, Cashbooks, Payments Books, 1854-1894 (Box 9)
- Scholarships in the University of the City of New York, 1855-1859 (Box 38)
- Scrapbook of Bills and Receipts, 1856-1866 (Box 3)
- Ledger and Cash book (2 ledgers), 1858-1875 (Box 26)
- Bellevue Hospital and Medical College Treasurer's Book, 1861-1867 (Box 27)
- Medical Department Treasurer's Ledgers (2 ledgers), 1861-1881 (Box 28)
- Bellevue Hospital and Medical College Cashbook and Ledger, 1868-1878 (Box 10)
- Payroll Books and Salary Lists, 1880-1900 (Box 11)
- University Building: Rent Rolls and Collector's Accounts (2 ledgers), 1891-1893 (Box 35)
- Journal, 1892-1900 (Box 12)
- Summary of Receipts and Expenditures, 1892-1895 (Box 14)
- Ledger, 1892-1900 (Box 13)
- Scrapbook, 1895-1896 (Box 37)
- Vouchers, 1895-1896 (Box 32)
- Interest Liability Shares, 1895-1899 (Box 29)
- Deem's Loan Fund and other accounts, 1895-1906 (Box 29)
- Financial Records, Bills, Address Book, 1896-1897 (Box 33)
- Fee Books, Financial Reports, Expenditure Reports, General Income Ledger, Student Rosters, 1896-1899 (Box 15)
- School of Pedagogy Cashbook, 1897-1901 (Box 36)
- Student Rosters, East 25th Street Property, Loan Fund, Cash Accounts, Income and Expenses, Payroll, University Accounts, 1897-1919 (Box 16)
- Journal, 1900-1925 (Box 17)
- Ledger, 1901-1911 (Box 18)
- Cashbook, 1901-1929 (Box 19)
- School of Pedagogy Women's Advisory Committee Cashbook, 1902-1917 (Box 36)
- Memorandum Ledger, 1903-1931 (Box 3)
- General Memorandum Ledger, 1908-1912 (Box 30)
- Rents Ledger, 1909-1913 (Box 30)
- Statement of Income and Expense of each school, 1909-1960 (Box 3)
- Ledger, 1911-1921 (Box 20)
- Ledger, Volume II, 1911-1921 (Box 21)
- Summer School Ledger, 1912 (Box 39)
- Journal of Expenditures, 1915-1916 (Box 23)
- School of Dentistry Ledger, 1915-1916 (Box 22)
- Daily Cash Balances, 1915-1920 (Box 24)
- National Trial Balance and Income Tax Deduction, 1919-1921 (Box 31)
- Ledger, 1920-1928 (Box 25)
- Financial Records - Cash Receipts, other than Fees, 1920-1922 (Volume Bound 1920-1922, 58(v))
- Financial Records - Journal, 1923-1924 (Volume Bound 1923-1924, 59(v))
- Financial Records - Cash Receipts, 1925-1926 (Volume Bound 1925-1926, 60(v))
- Financial Records - Cash Receipt Book, Cashbook, Voucher Record, Record of Audited Vouchers, 1922-1926 (Volume Bound 1922-1926, 63(v))
- Financial Records - Records of Cash Receipts, 1922-1923 (Volume Bound 1922-1923, 64(v))
- Financial Records - Cashbook, 1923-1924 (Volume Bound 1923-1924, 61(v))
- Financial Records - Voucher Record, 1923-1924 (Volume Bound 1923-1924, 62(v))
- Untitled - Index (Volume Bound Undated Index)